My dad used to tell me
كان والدي يقول لي
I had to be tough since I'm a man
كان علي أن أكون قاسياً منذ أن أصبحت رجلاً
and therefore, the leader of the family.
وبالتالي زعيم الأسرة.
Zen, come and have breakfast.
زين تعال وتناول الفطور
But Mom would tell Dad off if she heard him.
لكن أمي ستخبر أبي إذا سمعته.
Then she'd tell me it's okay to feel weak even if you're a man
ثم ستخبرني أنه لا بأس أن تشعر بالضعف حتى لو كنت رجلاً
if you need to do so.
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى القيام بذلك.
You're holding your father's present again.
أنت تحمل هدية والدك مرة أخرى.
Aren't you hungry?
ألست جائعا؟
Grandma, do you think Mom and Dad are going to miss us?
جدتي، هل تعتقدين أن أمي وأبي سيفتقداننا؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Just like how we miss them.
تمامًا كما نفتقدهم.
Don't worry, Grandma.
لا تقلقي يا جدتي.
Even though they're not here anymore,
على الرغم من أنهم لم يعودوا هنا بعد الآن،
I'll look after you.
سوف أعتنى بك.
Okay then.
حسنا إذا.
Dad,
أب،
Mom,
أم،
please be my strength from afar.
من فضلك كن قوتي من بعيد.
(The Rebound)
(القفزة)
(Directed by Tanwarin Sukkhapisit)
(إخراج تانوارين سوكابيسيت)
Ryu.
ريو.
Is this really the life you've chosen?
هل هذه حقا هي الحياة التي اخترتها؟
It's easy for you to say.
من السهل عليك أن تقول ذلك.
How can you possibly know?
كيف يمكنك أن تعرف؟
As for basketball,
أما بالنسبة لكرة السلة،
are you going to let someone tell you
هل ستدع أحدا يخبرك
to win
للفوز
or lose a game?
أو تخسر لعبة؟
Shut your mouth.
اصمت.
Seriously,
بجد،
who are you
من أنت
playing basketball for these days?
لعب كرة السلة لهذه الأيام؟
And you?
وأنت؟
Who do you play for every time you play?
لمن تلعب في كل مرة تلعب فيها؟
The people I love.
الناس الذين أحبهم.
Everyone who taught me to love basketball.
كل من علمني حب كرة السلة.
That makes two of us.
الذي يجعل اثنين منا.
So why are you doing it?
فلماذا تفعل ذلك؟
Why don't you follow the rules?
لماذا لا تتبع القواعد؟
Shut up.
اسكت.
Wait.
انتظر.
What now?
ماذا الان؟
Where do you live now?
أين تعيش الآن؟
I'll wash your shirt and return it to you.
سأغسل قميصك وأعيده إليك.
No need. You can have it.
لا حاجة.  تستطيع الحصول عليه.
But don't ever throw it away.
ولكن لا ترميها أبدًا.
I'll kill you if I find out you did.
سأقتلك إذا اكتشفت أنك فعلت ذلك.
Hey, you call that running? That's pathetic!
مهلا، هل تسمي ذلك جريا؟  هذا مثير للشفقة!
Do you think you're at Lumphini Park?
هل تعتقد أنك في حديقة لومفيني؟
Are you planning to do aerobics or tai chi afterward?
هل تخطط لممارسة التمارين الرياضية أو رياضة التاي تشي بعد ذلك؟
Put your back into it!
ضع ظهرك فيه!
Ugh!
قرف!
My mother can run faster than all of you.
تستطيع والدتي أن تجري أسرع منكم جميعًا.
I'm so exhausted!
أنا منهك جدا!
You're such a whiner.
أنت متذمر.
- It was only a run. - Move away.
- لقد كان مجرد تشغيل.  - الابتعاد.
It was only a run?
لقد كان مجرد تشغيل؟
- You're weak. - Shut up.
- كنت ضعيفا.  - اسكت.
- What?
- ماذا؟  - اسكت.
- Take this. - Hey, stop!
- خد هذا.  - مهلا توقف!
Hey!
يا!
Are you going to work, Zen?
هل ستذهب للعمل يا زين؟
About the coach, are you really going to let this happen?
بخصوص المدرب، هل ستترك هذا يحدث حقًا؟
We'll have to wait and see.
سيتعين علينا أن ننتظر ونرى.
But I won't let it go if he's just fooling around.
لكنني لن أترك الأمر إذا كان مجرد عبث.
Right, First.
الحق، أولا.
Can you help me prepare the court for practice tomorrow
هل يمكنك مساعدتي في إعداد المحكمة للتمرين غدًا
if you get here early?
إذا وصلت هنا في وقت مبكر؟
Sure. I'll see you then.
بالتأكيد.  سوف أراك بعد ذلك.
Here. I'll help you.
هنا.  سوف اساعدك.
You don't have to. You already showered.
ليس عليك أن تفعل ذلك.  لقد استحممت بالفعل.
I can take another shower, can't I?
يمكنني أخذ حمام آخر، أليس كذلك؟
Come on. Hand over the cloth.
تعال.  تسليم القماش.
Mm.
مم.
Have the guys on the team said anything?
هل قال أعضاء الفريق أي شيء؟
Should I be honest or polite?
هل يجب أن أكون صادقًا أم مهذبًا؟
Whoa.
قف.
If that's what you're saying,
إذا كان هذا ما تقوله،
then just be honest.
ثم كن صادقا.
Well, I don't know. It's only the beginning.
حسنا، أنا لا أعرف.  إنها البداية فقط.
It's only the beginning, I guess.
إنها البداية فقط، على ما أعتقد.
First,
أولاً،
do you mind helping me with something?
هل تمانع في مساعدتي بشيء ما؟
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Can you tell me
هل يمكن أن تخبرني
if you hear anything?
إذا سمعت أي شيء؟
Please? Can you?
لو سمحت؟  هل تستطيع؟
We don't have much time left,
لم يعد لدينا الكثير من الوقت،
and there's a game coming up.
وهناك لعبة قادمة.
Please help me
الرجاء مساعدتي
in case...
في حال...
I might be able to help our team get qualified.
ربما أستطيع مساعدة فريقنا في التأهل.
Please? Can you help me?
لو سمحت؟  هل بإمكانك مساعدتي؟
Please? I'm begging you.
لو سمحت؟  أتوسل إليك.
Oh, okay.
حسنا.
For real?
لريال مدريد؟
Mm.
مم.
Don't tell me I have to do that with you?
لا تقل لي أنني يجب أن أفعل ذلك معك؟
I'd rather not. It tickles.
أنا بالأحرى لا.  يدغدغ.
- Come on. Promise me. - No.
- تعال.  اوعدني.  - لا.
- First.
- لا. - أولا.
- Oh? - And the thumb.
- أوه؟  - والإبهام.
There.
هناك.
If you break the promise, you'll be dead the day after next.
إذا حنثت بالوعد، فسوف تموت في اليوم التالي.
Remember that.
تذكر ذلك.
Mm.
مم.
Pick up your pace!
التقط وتيرة الخاص بك!
Just like that!
مثل هذا تماما!
Hurry up!
أسرع - بسرعة!
Yes!
نعم!
That's it!
هذا كل شيء!
Hello? Your coffee's arrived.
مرحبًا؟  وصلت قهوتك.
I'm waiting near the front.
أنا أنتظر بالقرب من الجبهة.
Don't let him get past you!
لا تدع له تجاوز لك!
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Hey, what's with the foul play?
مهلا، ما هو مع اللعب كريهة؟
Foul play? Isn't that normal?
لعبة سيئة؟  أليس هذا طبيعيا؟
There are no rules here.
لا توجد قواعد هنا.
And don't forget
ولا تنسى
you were playing dirty last time.
كنت تلعب القذرة آخر مرة.
- You punk. - Hey.
- انت فاسق.  - يا.
If your friend can't play, doesn't that mean we win by default?
إذا كان صديقك لا يستطيع اللعب، ألا يعني ذلك أننا نفوز بشكل افتراضي؟
And the money's ours.
والمال لنا.
Stop right there.
توقف هناك.
Go and sit reserve.
اذهب واجلس احتياطيًا.
Can you get up?
هل تستطيع النهوض؟
I don't think so.
أنا لا أعتقد ذلك.
So? Are you going to forfeit?
لذا؟  هل ستخسر؟
Hey, you.
يا هذا.
What?
ماذا؟
Can you substitute for my friend?
هل يمكنك أن تحل محل صديقي؟
What? Me?
ماذا؟  أنا؟
Yes, you'll get 2,000 baht if we win.
نعم، سوف تحصل على 2000 باهت إذا فزنا.
You're in need of money, aren't you?
أنت في حاجة إلى المال، أليس كذلك؟
Come on.
تعال.
What kind of pass is that?
أي نوع من التمريرة هذا؟
Why didn't you catch it?
لماذا لم تقبض عليه؟
That was a bad pass.
لقد كانت تلك تمريرة سيئة.
It's okay. Get up.
لا بأس.  استيقظ.
What's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
He didn't bump into you that hard.
هو لم يصطدم بك بهذه القوة
Not that hard? Do you want to give it a try?
ليس بهذه الصعوبة؟  هل تريد أن تجربها؟
Hey!
يا!
You can continue the discussion at home, kids.
يمكنكم مواصلة المناقشة في المنزل أيها الأطفال.
Come on.
تعال.
Let's do it this way. I'll watch your back.
دعونا نفعل ذلك بهذه الطريقة.  سأراقب ظهرك.
What?
ماذا؟
What are you confused about?
ماذا الخلط حول؟
I said I'll watch your back if they're going to hurt you.
قلت أنني سأحمي ظهرك إذا كانوا سيؤذيونك.
Just keep scoring points.
فقط استمر في تسجيل النقاط.
Come on!
تعال!
Zen.
زين.
Yes!
نعم!
Go! Go!
يذهب!  يذهب!
Ryu, well done!
ريو، أحسنت!
Well done!
أحسنت!
Here.
هنا.
You did very well today.
لقد قمت بعمل جيد جدا اليوم.
Thank you, Boss.
شكرا لك يا رئيس.
Oh?
أوه؟
Why'd you stop like that?
لماذا توقفت هكذا؟
You're as clumsy as always.
أنت أخرق كما هو الحال دائما.
And you're annoying as always.
وأنت مزعج كما هو الحال دائما.
Here's your cut.
وهنا قطع الخاص بك.
Is this the reason why you're playing here?
هل هذا هو سبب لعبك هنا؟
Mm.
مم.
And where do you live now?
وأين تعيش الآن؟
Have you gone home at all?
هل ذهبت إلى المنزل على الإطلاق؟
Just take the money and go.
فقط خذ المال واذهب.
I'll only take this much.
سآخذ هذا القدر فقط.
How come?
كيف ذلك؟
You already paid for the coffee.
لقد دفعت بالفعل ثمن القهوة.
Don't you have to pay back your debt to those guys as well?
ألا يتعين عليك سداد ديونك لهؤلاء الرجال أيضًا؟
I overheard them shouting at you about it.
لقد سمعتهم يصرخون عليك بشأن هذا الأمر.
I already sorted that out. Can you give it a rest?
لقد قمت بالفعل بفرز ذلك.  هل يمكنك أن تعطيه قسطا من الراحة؟
Just take all of it.
فقط خذ كل ذلك.
Ryu.
ريو.
Come on.
تعال.
- Take it. - You keep it.
- خذها.  - احتفظ بها.
You'll be able to take your grandmom to a doctor too.
ستتمكن من اصطحاب جدتك إلى الطبيب أيضًا.
She asked about you
سألت عنك
when you disappeared at first.
عندما اختفيت في البداية
But honestly, she's still asking about you.
لكن بصراحة، لا تزال تسأل عنك.
Really?
حقًا؟
Mm.
مم.
Ryu.
ريو.
Your skill...
مهارتك...
is still the same as when we were in middle school.
لا يزال هو نفسه عندما كنا في المدرسة المتوسطة.
Haven't I improved at all?
لم أتحسن على الإطلاق؟
Now that you've mentioned it,
والآن بعد أن ذكرت ذلك،
you've gotten better.
لقد تحسنت.
Actually, I think you've become much more skilled.
في الواقع، أعتقد أنك أصبحت أكثر مهارة بكثير.
Mm.
مم.
The game just now
اللعبة الآن
reminded me of our middle school team.
ذكرني بفريق مدرستنا المتوسطة.
Now that I think about it,
الآن أن أفكر في ذلك،
I miss when we played basketball together.
أفتقد عندما لعبنا كرة السلة معًا.
Right, Zen.
الحق، زين.
There's somewhere I need to be. I have to go now.
هناك مكان يجب أن أكون فيه.  يجب أن أذهب الآن.
Don't come around here again if you can.
لا تأتي هنا مرة أخرى إذا كنت تستطيع.
Hey, have you been to school at all?
مهلا، هل ذهبت إلى المدرسة على الإطلاق؟
The school's not the place for me. You know that.
المدرسة ليست المكان المناسب لي  هل تعلم أن.
(Tonliu Computer Repair)
(تونليو لإصلاح الكمبيوتر)
I just want to remind you we have to submit the names next Friday.
أريد فقط أن أذكرك أنه يتعين علينا تقديم الأسماء يوم الجمعة المقبل.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
And who's going to play which position?
ومن سيلعب في أي مركز؟
I don't know. I'm still working on it.
لا أعرف.  أنا لا تزال تعمل على ذلك.
What? We might run out of time.
ماذا؟  ربما نفاد الوقت.
What's the problem?
ما هي المشكلة؟
PF.
الجبهة الوطنية.
- The power forward? - Mm.
- القوة إلى الأمام؟  - مم.
The one in control of the game who also scores.
الشخص المسيطر على المباراة والذي يسجل أيضًا.
I don't know who to pick from our lineup.
لا أعرف من سأختار من تشكيلتنا.
Dad!
أب!
- Dad! - What?
- أب!  - ماذا؟
Look at this.
أنظر إلى هذا.
What?
ماذا؟
Here's the power forward you've been looking for.
ها هي القوة إلى الأمام التي كنت تبحث عنها.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Right.
يمين.
I was...
انا كنت...
on the edge of my seat today.
على حافة مقعدي اليوم.
I bet a lot
أراهن كثيرا
of other people's money on you.
من أموال الآخرين عليك.
Good thing your friend came to the rescue,
من الجيد أن صديقك جاء لإنقاذك،
or I'd need to pack up and run away to Poipet.
أو سأحتاج إلى حزم أمتعتي والهرب إلى بويبيت.
Didn't you have any faith in me?
لم يكن لديك أي ثقة في لي؟
Of course I did.
بالطبع فعلت.
I'm a basketball player.
أنا لاعب كرة سلة.
I can tell
استطيع أن أقول
who's real and who's fake.
من الحقيقي ومن المزيف.
Your friend
صديقك
is quite good.
هو جيد جدا.
Should we get him to work with us?
هل يجب أن نجعله يعمل معنا؟
Leave him alone.
اتركه لوحده.
He's not suitable for the business.
إنه غير مناسب للعمل.
All right.
حسنًا.
You moron, you scared me for a second there.
أيها الأحمق، لقد أخافتني للحظة هناك.
Drink up. I bought it for you.
اشرب.  لقد اشتريتها لك.
Whoa, these look so yummy, Grandma.
واو، هذه تبدو لذيذة جدًا يا جدتي.
Don't they?
أليس كذلك؟
We can put them into these baskets according to the orders.
يمكننا وضعها في هذه السلال حسب الطلب.
Hm.
حسنًا.
Why is Khao Tom Mat always in a pair?
لماذا يكون خاو توم مات دائمًا في زوج؟
You're a curious one, aren't you?
أنت شخص فضولي، أليس كذلك؟
I don't know either.
أنا لا أعرف أيضا.
But back in the olden days, they said
لكنهم قالوا في الأيام الخوالي
it was the dessert of lovers.
وكانت حلوى العشاق.
Young couples would bring it to the temple as a merit offering
كان الأزواج الشباب يحضرونه إلى المعبد كعرض استحقاق
so their love life would prosper.
حتى تزدهر حياتهم العاطفية.
Oh.
أوه.
I thought a single one wouldn't be filling enough,
اعتقدت أن واحدة واحدة لن تكون كافية،
and that's why there are two.
ولهذا السبب هناك اثنان.
What brought you to that conclusion?
ما الذي أوصلك إلى هذا الاستنتاج؟
You really are a scholarship student.
أنت حقا طالب منحة دراسية.
It's a sports scholarship, not an academic one.
إنها منحة رياضية وليست أكاديمية.
I don't do that well in school.
أنا لا أفعل ذلك بشكل جيد في المدرسة.
Says who? My grandson is one smart cookie.
من تكلم؟  حفيدي هو أحد ملفات تعريف الارتباط الذكية.
You're a genius.
انت عبقري.
And you're the best at bragging about your grandson.
وأنت الأفضل في التفاخر بحفيدك.
- Grandma. - Hm?
- الجدة.  - هم؟
Do you remember Ryu?
هل تتذكر ريو؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Why? Have you found him?
لماذا؟  هل وجدته؟
Yes.
نعم.
I found him near where I'm working part-time.
لقد وجدته بالقرب من المكان الذي أعمل فيه بدوام جزئي.
Oh, that's great.
اه هذا عظيم.
How strange. He turned up all of a sudden
كم هو غريب.  لقد ظهر فجأة
and disappeared all of a sudden.
واختفت فجأة.
Invite him over sometime.
ادعوه في وقت ما.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
- Mm. - I'll bring him over.
- مم.  - سأحضره.
By the way, are you going to work at the pool?
بالمناسبة، هل ستعمل في حمام السباحة؟
Of course, I'm super stingy.
بالطبع، أنا بخيل للغاية.
I'll never miss a day of work.
لن أفتقد يومًا من العمل أبدًا.
Bring on the riches.
جلب على الثروات.
Cheers.
هتافات.
It's so strong.
انها قوية جدا.
Boss?
رئيس؟
Enjoy yourself. I'll come back later.
استمتع.  سأعود في وقت لاحق
There's no need.
ليس هناك حاجة.
We know each other through and through,
نحن نعرف بعضنا البعض من خلال،
and you're embarrassed over this?
وكنت محرجا من هذا؟
Sit.
يجلس.
- Go and look after him. - Yes, Boss.
- اذهب واعتني به.  - أجل يا رئيس.
I'll pass.
سوف أمر
Let's get to the point.
دعنا نصل الى اتفاق.
I don't think so.
أنا لا أعتقد ذلك.
Go on.
تابع.
I think your friend, Ryu,
أعتقد أن صديقك، ريو،
has grown up quite a lot this year.
لقد كبرت كثيرًا هذا العام.
Do you remember? You told me
هل تذكر؟  قلت لي
you were going to bring him to me.
كنت ذاهب لإحضاره لي.
When?
متى؟
He's preparing for a game.
إنه يستعد لمباراة.
I don't think now's the right time.
لا أعتقد أن هذا هو الوقت المناسب.
Who gets to say when the time's right or wrong?
من يستطيع أن يقول متى يكون الوقت مناسبًا أم خطأ؟
All of you, get out.
جميعكم، اخرجوا.
Boss,
رئيس،
I'm just
انا فقط
doing my best to take care of your interest.
أبذل قصارى جهدي لرعاية اهتمامك.
You should know how much money Ryu's been making for us.
يجب أن تعرف مقدار الأموال التي كان يجنيها "ريو" لنا.
A racehorse like him
حصان سباق مثله
doesn't have a very long shelf life.
ليس لديها مدة صلاحية طويلة جدًا.
What if he gets injured?
ماذا لو أصيب؟
Like you?
مثلك؟
You know
أنت تعرف
I'll never
أنا لن
abandon my people,
أتخلى عن شعبي
even if they can't play.
حتى لو لم يتمكنوا من اللعب.
Go and get him.
اذهب واحصل عليه.
You keep
إحتفظ
talking about him.
نتحدث عنه.
Your words are
كلماتك هي
hurting my feelings.
إيذاء مشاعري.
Are you...
أنت...
going to give it to me tonight?
هل ستعطيني هذه الليلة؟
If that's what you want.
اذا كان هذا ما تريده.
Can I even refuse?
هل يمكنني حتى أن أرفض؟
Hey!
يا!
Hey! Hey!
يا!  يا!
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
Are you really okay?
هل أنت بخير حقا؟
Mm.
مم.
Did you get a cramp?
هل أصبت بتشنج؟
No, I was diving.
لا، كنت أغوص.
What?
ماذا؟
Diving?
الغوص؟
Then why were you still like a log?
إذن لماذا كنت لا تزال مثل السجل؟
You really scared me.
لقد أخافتني حقًا.
But anyway, thanks a lot.
ولكن على أية حال، شكرا جزيلا.
I'm Atom.
أنا أتوم.
You?
أنت؟
Zen.
زين.
Hm.
حسنًا.
Do you like swimming?
هل تحب السباحة؟
Do you come here often?
هل تأتي هنا عادة؟
No,
لا،
I'm working here part-time.
أنا أعمل هنا بدوام جزئي.
See?
يرى؟
- Oh. - That's right.
- أوه.  - صحيح.
Saturdays and Sundays.
أيام السبت والأحد.
Anyway, I should get back to cleaning the pool.
على أية حال، يجب أن أعود لتنظيف حوض السباحة.
Should I give you a hand?
هل يجب أن أعطيك يد المساعدة؟
No!
لا!
You're a customer here.
أنت عميل هنا.
I might lose my job if the owner sees you working.
قد أفقد وظيفتي إذا رآك المالك تعمل.
I have to go.
يجب على  أن أذهب.
Hello? What's up, First?
مرحبًا؟  ما الأمر، أولا؟
Huh?
هاه؟
Say what?
يقول ما؟
(Dad: Where are you? Why aren't you home?)
(الأب: أين أنت؟ لماذا لست في المنزل؟)
(I went out swimming.)
(خرجت للسباحة.)
(Dad: Good. Don't overexert yourself or you might pull a muscle.)
(الأب: جيد. لا تجهد نفسك وإلا قد تشد عضلة.)
First, I thought you said you got beaten up.
أولاً، اعتقدت أنك قلت أنك تعرضت للضرب.
- And what's... - Thanks for coming.
- وما هو... - شكرا لحضوركم.
Should we play a one-on-one game?
هل يجب أن نلعب لعبة فردية؟
With you, old man?
معك أيها العجوز؟
Zen, can you compete against this poser?
زين، هل يمكنك التنافس ضد هذا المتصنع؟
Why do I have to?
لماذا يجب أن؟
Just do it.
افعل ذلك.
I'll coach you. Just follow my orders.
سأقوم بتدريبك.  فقط اتبع أوامري.
It'll be an easy win.
سيكون الفوز سهلا.
I won't do it. It's a waste of time.
لن أفعل ذلك.  انها مضيعة للوقت.
Scared, huh?
خائفة، هاه؟
- Me? Scared? - Mm.
- أنا؟  مقدس؟  - مم.
You came all the way here to challenge my guy.
لقد أتيت إلى هنا لتحدي رجلي.
Aren't you going to cough up a little?
لن السعال قليلا؟
How does 5,000 baht sound?
كيف يبدو صوت 5000 باهت؟
So we won't be wasting our precious time.
لذلك لن نضيع وقتنا الثمين.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Deal.
اتفاق.
He didn't even ask me.
ولم يسألني حتى.
Since we're betting on this game,
وبما أننا نراهن على هذه اللعبة،
should we switch from a spin ball to something a little risky?
هل يجب أن نتحول من الكرة الدوارة إلى شيء محفوف بالمخاطر قليلاً؟
If not, then what?
إذا لم يكن الأمر كذلك، فماذا؟
A jump ball.
كرة القفز.
All right.
حسنًا.
Ready?
مستعد؟
Go!
يذهب!
One to zero.
واحد إلى صفر.
Let's keep going, my dear Ryu!
دعنا نستمر يا عزيزي ريو!
Dad, is Zen going to be okay?
أبي، هل سيكون زين بخير؟
Zen.
زين.
Don't get so close to him.
لا تقترب منه كثيراً.
He's good at reaching for the ball.
إنه جيد في الوصول إلى الكرة.
He's probably good in the semi-circle too.
ربما يكون جيدًا في نصف الدائرة أيضًا.
Do you want to try forcing him to shoot from further away?
هل تريد محاولة إجباره على إطلاق النار من مسافة أبعد؟
You might have a better chance.
قد يكون لديك فرصة أفضل.
Yes, Coach.
نعم المدرب.
Out of bounds. Switch.
خارج الحدود.  يُحوّل.
You might have to switch up your game.
قد تضطر إلى تبديل لعبتك.
Big mouth.
فم كبير.
Take the shot then.
خذ اللقطة إذن.
Do it.
افعلها.
Switch.
يُحوّل.
- Yes! - Dad,
- نعم!  - أب،
he did it!
هو فعل ذلك!
Ryu, why did you let him score?
ريو، لماذا تركته يسجل؟
Let him score?
السماح له بالتسجيل؟
My dad's guy is much better than yours.
رجل والدي أفضل بكثير من رجلك.
That sucker?
هذا المصاصة؟
That's right.
صحيح.
The first to score in this round
أول من سجل في هذه الجولة
wins.
يفوز.
Hang in there, Ryu.
انتظر هناك، ريو.
Keep going, Zen!
استمر يا زين
You're good.
أنت جيدة أو أنت طيب.
What should we do now, Coach?
ماذا يجب أن نفعل الآن أيها المدرب؟
I don't think...
لا أعتقد...
he's going to let you shoot from a distance this time.
سيسمح لك بإطلاق النار من مسافة بعيدة هذه المرة.
Name your strategy, sir.
قم بتسمية استراتيجيتك يا سيدي.
Okay.
تمام.
If you win,
اذا انت ربحت،
I'll give you 2,000.
سأعطيك 2000.
How about 2,500?
ماذا عن 2500؟
Gas money.
نقود للبنزين.
Okay, okay.
حسنا حسنا.
But he probably wants to keep close to you this time.
لكنه ربما يريد أن يبقى قريبًا منك هذه المرة.
He's going to expect you to take the shot from afar. Therefore,
سيتوقع منك أن تلتقط الصورة من بعيد.  لذلك،
if you want to make yourself unpredictable,
إذا كنت تريد أن تجعل نفسك غير متوقع،
you have to play unpredictably.
عليك أن تلعب بشكل غير متوقع.
Yes, Coach.
نعم المدرب.
Go.
يذهب.
Hang in there, Zen.
انتظر هناك، زين.
They're inside the semi-circle.
إنهم داخل نصف الدائرة.
Piece of cake.
قطعة من الكعك.
Well done, Zen.
أحسنت يا زين.
- That was excellent! - Ugh!
- كان ذلك ممتازا!  - قرف!
Darn it!
رتقها!
What did you tell him?
بماذا أخبرته؟
If you want to find out,
إذا كنت تريد معرفة ذلك،
join the school's team. Then I'll tell you.
الانضمام إلى فريق المدرسة.  ثم سأخبرك.
See you tomorrow.
أراك غدا.
Thank you for supporting the school's basketball team.
شكرا لدعمكم فريق كرة السلة في المدرسة.
I'll see you in the gymnasium after school tomorrow.
سوف أراك في صالة الألعاب الرياضية بعد المدرسة غدا.
There's still next time.
لا يزال هناك في المرة القادمة.
Let's stop waiting. We're wasting time.
دعونا نتوقف عن الانتظار.  نحن نضيع الوقت.
But it's only four.
لكنها أربعة فقط.
Ryu's probably on his way.
من المحتمل أن يكون "ريو" في طريقه.
Have it your way.
افعلها بطريقتك.
But don't expect much from that kind of guy.
لكن لا تتوقع الكثير من هذا النوع من الرجال.
Come on.
تعال.
Gather around!
يجتمع حول!
Oh? Where's Ryu?
أوه؟  أين ريو؟
I don't think he's coming, Coach.
لا أعتقد أنه سيأتي، أيها المدرب.
He's probably busy, Dad. Oops, Coach.
ربما هو مشغول يا أبي.  عفوًا أيها المدرب.
Should I go and get him?
هل يجب أن أذهب وأحضره؟
No, it's okay if he doesn't want to come.
لا، لا بأس إذا كان لا يريد أن يأتي.
All right. The rest of you,
حسنًا.  بقية لكم،
give me 50 laps around the court!
أعطني 50 لفة حول الملعب!
- Yes, Coach!
- نعم المدرب!  - نعم المدرب!
Get going.
استمر.
Ryu,
ريو،
there's a big game coming up.
هناك لعبة كبيرة قادمة.
High-rollers are coming.
بكرات عالية قادمة.
Prepare yourself for it.
جهز نفسك لذلك.
Hey.
يا.
You're not saying anything
أنت لا تقول أي شيء
but you know what to do, right?
لكنك تعرف ماذا تفعل، أليس كذلك؟
Yes.
نعم.
Here you go, Dad.
هنا تذهب، أبي.
You should try and get Ryu again.
يجب أن تحاول الحصول على ريو مرة أخرى.
We'll be a lot better if we have him with us.
سنكون أفضل بكثير إذا كان معنا.
He doesn't want to come, and I don't like forcing anyone.
هو لا يريد أن يأتي، وأنا لا أحب إجبار أي شخص.
Okay, Coach.
حسنًا أيها المدرب.
But let me tell you something. We have to submit the names soon.
لكن دعني اخبرك بأمر ما.  علينا أن نقدم الأسماء قريبا.
And our next match is in a few weeks.
ومباراتنا القادمة ستكون بعد بضعة أسابيع.
You know the skill level of the others.
أنت تعرف مستوى مهارة الآخرين.
How are things?
كيف هي الأمور؟
I heard you got enough team members.
سمعت أن لديك ما يكفي من أعضاء الفريق.
I did, but...
فعلت، ولكن...
But if we want to win,
لكن إذا أردنا الفوز
we have to find more.
علينا أن نجد المزيد.
You have to hurry up.
عليك أن تسرع.
If our team can't compete,
إذا لم يتمكن فريقنا من المنافسة،
the school board won't officially hire you.
لن يقوم مجلس إدارة المدرسة بتعيينك رسميًا.
I know. Stop with the threats, won't you?
أنا أعرف.  توقف عن التهديدات، أليس كذلك؟
- The team's in your hands now. - I know.
- الفريق بين يديك الآن.  - أنا أعرف.
That's it!
هذا كل شيء!
Go! Go! Go!
يذهب!  يذهب!  يذهب!
Hey, Ryu!
مهلا، ريو!
Get up!
استيقظ!
You can't lose this one!
لا يمكنك أن تفقد هذا!
Ryu!
ريو!
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
Time out.
نفذ الوقت.
If you insist on staying in the semi-circle,
إذا أصررت على البقاء في نصف الدائرة،
you'll just keep getting hurt.
سوف تستمر في التعرض للأذى.
Lure them out
استدرجهم للخارج
and let your friends set a screen.
والسماح لأصدقائك بتعيين الشاشة.
Keep it up!
استمر!
Hurry up!
أسرع - بسرعة!
Mister?
سيد؟
Here's your cut.
وهنا قطع الخاص بك.
Keep the money.
الحفاظ على المال.
Seriously,
بجد،
are you really going to keep doing this?
هل أنت حقا سوف تستمر في القيام بذلك؟
This place suits me best.
هذا المكان يناسبني أكثر.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Then...
ثم...
why don't you look happy when you're playing?
لماذا لا تبدو سعيدا عندما تلعب؟
I'm happy.
أنا سعيد.
Okay.
تمام.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
But during the game just now,
لكن خلال المباراة الآن،
your eyes were so empty,
عيناك كانتا فارغتين للغاية
not like when you were playing against Zen.
ليس كما لو كنت تلعب ضد زين.
Think about it. You can give me an answer later.
فكر في الأمر.  يمكنك أن تعطيني الجواب في وقت لاحق.
Gather around!
يجتمع حول!
Come on.
تعال.
That's enough for this morning.
هذا يكفي لهذا الصباح.
Get changed and head to class. Okay?
غيّر ملابسك وتوجه إلى الفصل.  تمام؟
Hang on, sir.
انتظر يا سيدي.
We have to submit the names tomorrow, but we're still short.
علينا أن نقدم الأسماء غدا، لكننا لا نزال قصيرين.
I'd like to introduce you to our newest member,
أود أن أعرفكم بالعضو الجديد لدينا،
Ryu.
ريو.
Go on. Introduce yourself.
تابع.  عرفنى بنفسك.
I'm Ryu.
أنا ريو.
I'm the power forward.
أنا القوة إلى الأمام.
Get yourselves ready for class. I'll see you later this evening.
جهزوا أنفسكم للفصل.  سوف أراك في وقت لاحق هذا المساء.
Anyway, look after Ryu, Captain Zen.
على أية حال، اعتني بـ ريو، أيها الكابتن زين.
Why did you come back all of a sudden?
لماذا عدت فجأة؟
Didn't you say you weren't going to play for the school team anymore?
ألم تقل أنك لن تلعب لفريق المدرسة بعد الآن؟
I wonder when the newbie's going to stir up trouble.
أتساءل متى سيثير الوافد الجديد المشاكل؟
It's like having a ticking time bomb on the team.
إنه مثل وجود قنبلة موقوتة في الفريق.
I don't think Ryu's that kind of person.
لا أعتقد أن ريو هو هذا النوع من الأشخاص.
Hey! Do you think you're so tough?
يا!  هل تعتقد أنك صعب للغاية؟
Hey!
يا!
Why are you guys fighting?
لماذا تتقاتلون يا رفاق؟
I always look bad in everyone's eyes anyway.
أنا دائما أبدو سيئا في أعين الجميع على أي حال.
I want to pay you back
أريد أن أدفع لك
for jumping in the pool to save me.
للقفز في حوض السباحة لإنقاذي.
Seeing you smile makes me feel better.
رؤيتك تبتسم تجعلني أشعر بتحسن.
Did you remind Ryu?
هل ذكرت ريو؟
You know how much I lost because of him last time?
هل تعلم كم خسرت بسببه آخر مرة؟
I hope you won't disappoint me tonight.
آمل أنك لن تخيب ظني الليلة.